consider the set of positive real
numbers and draw the graph of the
function f ofx = 1 /x on this domain the
derivative of this function is frime of
x = -1 /x^2 if we consider the input x =
1 we see that the point on the graph is
1 1 and the derivative frime of 1 is 1
this means that the tangent line to the
function 1 /x at x = 1 has a slope of -
1 and therefore the equation of the
tangent line is Y = 2 - x because FX =
1X concave up we see that every point on
the tangent line lies below the
corresponding point for the same x value
on the curve 1/x this means that in
general 2 - x is less than or equal to 1
/x by adding X to both sides we see that
for any positive real number x 2 is less
than or equal to 1x + x can you see from
the diagram when equality holds